sync and corrections: othelo
www.addic7ed.com
Okay.
Begin.
My name is Nora Elizabeth
Jamison Durst.
Date of birth: 11/18/1979.
This is a copy of today's paper.
I hereby indemnify all individuals
for the procedure that's about to occur.
I'm of sound mind and body,
and I'm acting of my own free will.
- That's it.
- Stop.
Something wrong?
Nothing, it-- It's fine.
What did she say?
She wants you to do it again.
Why do you want me to do it again?
Because I do not believe you.
Excuse me?
Excuse me, but you're lying.
You're just...
You're just saying
what we want to hear.
You invited me here,
and then you rejected me.
But I sat outside your house
all night and I followed you here,
so you'd have no choice
but to let me get into your machine.
So, I don't give a shit
what you want to hear.
And I don't lie.
Can you say
your children's names?
- What?
- Your children.
Do you think you can say their names?
Erin and Jeremy.
I meant in your statement.
Would you like to try again?
Okay.
My name is Nora Elizabeth
Jamison Durst.
I was born on November 18th, 1979.
This is a copy of today's paper,
because today is the day
I'm leaving to be with them.
I'm leaving to be with my children,
Erin and Jeremy.
I'm ready to go now.
We prefer to give
a more thorough orientation,
but since we were in the process
of moving on,
you'll just have to bear with us.
Was that a person?
It's a fossil.
The person is gone.
Maybe they'll let you keep mine.
As soon as we've administered
your saline drip,
you will disrobe outside the truck.
Once you are inside, you will see
the event chamber at the far end.
You just walk to it.
You may experience nausea or discomfort
as you pass by
the undulating laser array
while it cycles up.
Do not touch the array.
Step inside the event chamber,
close the exit port behind you,
and turn the latch to the left.
Hard to the left. It'll stick.
Then pull your knees
towards your chest
and hold them there.
- Okay?
- Okay.
We will be monitoring you
from inside there.
Once inside the event chamber,
you will be able to hear us
and we will be able to hear you.
When you're ready,
we will start the ignition sequence.
You will hear three tones.
After the third tone,
the chamber will fill up with fluid.
The fluid will have
the same consistency as water,
but it is not water.
It contains metals
that will be irradiated.
Once this occurs,
the fluid will solidify.
Do not ingest or breathe in
any of the fluid
as your lungs would also solidify
upon transport.
Can you hold your breath
for 30 seconds?
Yes.
Well...
then that's it.
Activity.
Pole dancing.
Um, noun.
Gecko.
Gecko. Excellent.
Okay, last one.
Man's name.
Antonio.
Antonio. Perfect.
Okay, here we go.
"Nora Elizabeth Jamison Durst,
Age 417..."
"...was vaporized by a consortium
of international physicists
last Tuesday outside Never Never Land.
Miss Durst was born
and raised in Cairo, Egypt..."
- Mmm.
- "...Where she returned after college
to squeeze a family..."
"...her spiffy husband, Doug Durst,
and her beloved geese,
Jeremy and Erin.
Admired by her coworkers,
she was a longtime employee
at the Department
of the Sudden Diarrhea."
That's disgusting.
"In her spare time,
Miss Durst enjoyed crosswords,
exposing frauds, and pole dancing.
She is survived,
at least temporarily,
by her terminally ill gecko,
Matthew Jamison."
"As she lives on in our memories,
and in the Great Antonio in the sky."
Mm.
"There will be no funeral
or memorial service."
Mm.
Oh, God bless Matt Libs.
I couldn't ask for a better obituary.
Happy to oblige.
You sending me those things
is what got me through
Hellfire and Damnation.
The horrible Bible camp
that Grandma and Pop-Pop
used to send me off to
in the Adirondacks?
It wasn't Hellfire and Damnation,
it was Camp Holy Spirit.
Potato, pah-ta-toe.
You were so young with the pigtails.
- What were you, eight years old?
- Seven.
Do you remember what you said to me
when you put me on the bus?
"Brush your teeth"?
You said...
You said that I was
the bravest girl on Earth.
And every time you sent me a letter
with a new Matt Lib in it,
that's who it was addressed to--
"The Bravest Girl on Earth."
I forgot about that.
You drive me fucking nuts.
But you've always been
a great gecko, Matt.
If I was a great gecko,
I'd be trying to talk you out of this.
You're great because you're not trying.
I'm scared.
I'll be fine.
Of course you will. You always are.
I'm scared of what'll happen
when I go back to Mary.
And I'm scared of the chemicals
they're going to put in my body
to try and make me better, and...
I'm scared it won't work.
I'm scared of dying, Nora.
I'm scared my son
will grow up without me,
forget my face,
forget the sound of my voice.
But most of all,
I'm scared that I'll survive.
Because if I do...
how can I ever stand
in front of a room full of people
and convince them
that I have the answers
when I have no idea
what the fuck I'm talking about?
Do you want to come with me instead?
I think, dear sister,
that defeats the purpose.
What are you going
to tell people about me?
About what happened here?
Whatever you want me to.
Are you ready?
Of course she's ready.
She's the bravest girl on Earth.
- Give it to me!
- No!
- It's mine!
- You don't need it anymore!
Give her the blanket.
Two hands like a big girl. Good deal.
I'm hungry, Mom. I'm hungry!
- I'm hungry, too!
- No phones at the table.
- Yours is out, too.
- I'm waiting to hear about the job.
- This is important, too.
- I want food!
I want food! I want food!
- It's coming, buddy.
- I want food!
- Jeremy. Hey.
- Cut it out.
God damn it, I said two hands!
Dr. Eden over radio:
Nora, can you hear me?
Yes.
Your brother is here with us.
Hello, Nora.
Hi, Matt.
I love you.
I love you, too.
We're going to begin, Nora.
I was worried you'd forgotten.
Don't usually get
so many so close together.
Love is in the air.
A little extra for your trouble.
Sarah, does the name Kevin
mean anything to you?
No.
Are you sure?
Because a man calling himself that
came by yesterday.
He had a photo. A photo of you.
Did you tell him anything?
No, of course not.
But I think he knew I was lying.
Nora?
Kevin.
Kevin Garvey.
I don't know if you remember me.
I was the chief of police in Mapleton.
We don't know each other really well.
We only talked a couple times, really.
There was this dance,
a Christmas dance at the high school.
We just had a really nice conversation.
Yeah.
In the hallway.
I don't expect you to remember.
It was a long time ago.
What are you doing?
Well, um,
I've been kind of wandering
around Australia on vacation.
I-- Just kind of getting off the grid.
You know, trying to avoid
the touristy stuff.
I like to get a little lost, you know?
Anyway, I was--
I'm in that little town
down the road,
and I saw you riding your bike.
And I thought to myself,
"Holy shit, I think that's Nora Durst."
And, so, I found out where you lived.
And here you are.
- That's not what happened.
- Sorry?
You showed a picture of me
to the nun at the convent.
That's how you found out where I lived.
- Why would I have a picture of you?
- I just came from there.
- She told me that you asked if I--
- Are you married?
What?
Are you married
or are you seeing somebody?
I noticed you weren't wearing
a wedding ring.
And I saw that they were having
a dance in town tonight.
And when I saw you riding your bike,
it reminded me...
how I had always wished
I had asked you
to dance.
Anyway, I know it sounds crazy,
but I felt a connection.
So, you know, here we are
in the middle of nowhere
bumping into each other,
and I'm only here for the night,
and I figured, uh, you know,
if I didn't ask you to dance tonight...
I'll never forgive myself.
You need to leave now.
Okay.
I get it.
A guy you barely remember
shows up on your doorstep,
asks you to go
on a date with him, but...
I had to try.
Please just go.
I'll be there if you change your mind.
They shut down all of Main Street,
so you're not gonna be able to miss it.
It's good to see you, Nora.
- Hello?
- Did you tell him?
- Nora?
I-- I don't understand
what you're asking me.
Kevin, fucking Kevin. He's here.
- He found me.
- What? He's-- He's there in Australia?
Did you tell him where I was, Laurie?
No. No, I didn't.
- Because if you did, just say so, and I--
- I didn't.
We established boundaries
the first time you called me.
Clear boundaries.
I don't tell you
about the people here,
and I don't tell the people here
about you.
I would never betray that, Nora.
Then how did he find me?
How did he say he found you?
He said that he was here on vacation
and he spotted me.
And then he came to my house,
and he knocked on my door,
and he acted like we were
just casual acquaintances
from Mapleton years back,
like-- Like we were never together.
Like-- Like none of it happened.
Huh.
"Huh?" What's that mean? "Huh?"
Well, I'm just surprised, that's all.
It's a very un-Kevin-like thing to do.
Is he crazy?
Does he seem crazy?
No. He seemed happy.
Huh.
Would you please
stop fucking saying that?
Okay.
Why-- Why is he doing this?
I don't know.
Did he say anything else?
- He asked me to a dance.
- A dance?
I guess there's a dance
in town tonight,
and he asked me to go.
And you don't want to?
- No.
- What do you want?
Well, I want him to leave me alone.
- Then why are you calling me?
- What?
Well, I can't make him
leave you alone.
I'm half a world away,
so why did you call me?
I called you because I thought
you told him where I was.
Come on, you know
I didn't tell him that.
You called me
because you wanted me to say
it's okay to go to the dance.
I do not want to go
to the fucking dance!
Gotcha.
But if you did, it's okay.
Jesus Christ, Laurie.
Same time next week?
Where are your beads?
- Excuse me?
- Your beads. You need beads.
- Here, take one of mine.
- No, thank you.
You came.
It's a wedding.
I know.
You told me it was a dance.
People are dancing.
- Were you even invited?
- Yeah, of course I was.
Um... that's Eddie.
He can take a tractor apart,
put it back together blindfolded.
Allegedly.
And that's Aggie.
She was in the Army.
She left. Too many rules.
I bumped into them at the hotel bar.
They told me if I didn't come,
they'd be angry with me.
How did you find me, Kevin?
I'm on vacation in Australia.
I saw you ride by on your bike.
This is the middle of nowhere.
Why would you come here on vacation?
My father came Down Under a while back
and told me it was an amazing place,
so I just wanted to see for myself.
So, you're saying
you've never been here before.
This is your first time in Australia.
Uh-huh.
You're really gonna keep this up?
Keep what up?
So, you and me,
we only talked that one time
at that Christmas dance in Mapleton.
- Yeah.
- Mm-hmm.
What about the courthouse?
We got our divorces on the same day
and ran into each other.
I asked you to go to Miami.
- You asked me to go to Miami?
- Miami.
Yes.
But we were strangers?
And you're giving me a hard time
about inviting you to a dance?
It's a wedding.
You must have me confused
with someone else.
Because if you asked me
to go to Miami with you,
I definitely would've gone.
I love Miami.
So-- So, you never left?
You've been a cop
in Mapleton all this time?
Uh-huh.
Then you knew my brother,
Matt Jamison.
I was hoping
you were gonna come to the funeral.
We said our goodbyes in person.
It was a beautiful service.
Over 400 people came.
Mary gave the eulogy.
She really loved him.
There was a lot to love.
How are Jill and Tom?
You remember my kids' names?
Yeah.
I remember.
It's a little creepy,
but I am impressed.
Jill's great.
She married a great guy.
They have a daughter together.
Penelope. About a year old now.
And I'm a fucking grandpa.
Tommy's marriage
didn't work out so great.
But he landed on his feet,
like he always does.
- What about you?
- Me?
Did you ever get married again?
No.
Why not?
Because I'm still holding a candle
for you.
I find that hard to believe.
My mom died when I was nine.
My dad never remarried, so...
People hold candles, Nora.
- How is your dad?
- He's fantastic.
Jesus!
- He's 91 and he's still kicking.
- He must be immortal.
Oh, runs in the family, right?
- I'm not immortal.
- Oh?
Says who?
My cardiologist.
I had a condition.
It was undiagnosed my whole life.
A couple years back,
I had a heart attack.
A pretty-- pretty bad one.
But if they hadn't
diagnosed the condition,
then I wouldn't have known
I had had it,
and blah, blah, blah, so...
They just cut me open,
put in a pacemaker.
- Really?
- Yeah, really.
Wanna see my scar?
She came!
You said she wouldn't come.
Oh, I'm just as surprised as you are.
- Oops.
- Aggie, this is Nora.
- Nora, this is Aggie.
- Congratulations.
- He didn't think you were coming.
- Yeah, you mentioned that.
Nice of you to get
all dressed up for my wedding.
I'm sorry, I didn't know
it was a wedding.
I'm just fucking with you.
She's very serious.
Yeah.
Wouldn't have it any other way.
All right, that's enough chitchat.
Did you write your messages?
I gave mine to the nun.
Hi.
What about you, sweetheart?
Want to write a message of love
to send out to the world?
No, thank you.
And she's a romantic, too.
All right, let's get these over with!
Where the fuck's Eddie?
What did you tell her about us?
I told her I had a crush on a girl
and I wanted to chase after her,
but I didn't know what to say.
All right, everyone,
settle down.
I'm talking now!
Oi! Listen up, fuckwits!
All right, dearest family,
beloved friends,
and Russell.
Oi!
Eddie and I just wanna thank you all
for being here on our special day
to drink our alcohol free of charge.
Sweetheart, I am so happy
that we're gonna spend
the rest of our lives together.
And now that you've married me,
I have a confession.
I think I might be pregnant.
- No!
- Not to worry, love.
- It's yours, probably.
- Oh!
All right,
let's get to the ooey-gooey.
We have gathered your notes
and attached them
to these beautiful birds.
And now we are going to set them free
so they can fly off
to every corner of the world,
spreading those messages of love
to people everywhere.
Aw!
All right, Sister.
Release the birds!
What did you write?
That's for me to know
and some lonely Eskimo to find out.
Isn't that romantic, eh?
Yeah, let's hear it for the love birds!
Whoo!
See, if only life was just about love.
But it's about temptation.
It's about failure.
It's about weakness.
You know what I'm talking about,
don't you, Sister?
It's about sin, yeah.
And everybody here knows
I've made my fair share of mistakes,
but there is a very big difference
between a sin and a mistake.
Because a mistake
is just fucking up, hmm?
But a sin-- hoo-hoo.
A sin is when you know
something is wrong
and you do it anyway.
So, Aggie,
my darling wife,
my sun and my stars,
I look forward to a lifetime
of fucking up with you.
But I hereby swear
I will never sin again.
Aw!
Now bring out that fucking goat!
Yeah!
Hello! In biblical times,
a goat was designated
to be driven into the desert
with the sins
of the community upon it.
So...
...let these beads represent our sins.
Unburden yourselves, friends.
Then Russell will drive the scapegoat
deep into the bush, far from here,
so we can start over
untainted by our past mistakes.
At least they didn't sacrifice it.
Have you ever seen
somebody sacrifice a goat?
No.
That'd be weird.
Three, four.
- One, two, three, four.
- Al, don't count, don't say four,
'cause I'm gonna be on you.
How did you find me, Kevin?
I'm on vacation in Australia.
I can't do this.
Why not?
Because it's not true.
Evening.
- Sarah.
- What did you do with my birds?
I let them go just like I always do.
What's wrong?
What's wrong
is that they didn't come back.
Did you give them the seed
that I gave you?
Yes, of course.
And-- And you didn't feed them
right before you let them go, did you?
No, of course not.
I did everything the same.
- Then where are they?
- I don't know.
Those birds are trained
to do one thing,
just one thing,
and that's to come home,
so you must've done
something different.
Maybe they're delivering
the messages of love.
It's great that your newlyweds believe
that a bird with a range of 50 miles
is gonna carry their stupid poetry
to Timbuktu,
but don't sell that bullshit to me.
I'm not trying to sell you anything.
It's just a nicer story.
Who was that man?
What man?
The man I just saw leaving.
You mean Father Brian.
He's the only man
permitted in the convent.
Does Father Brian ride a motorcycle?
- No.
- Well, this man did.
And he was climbing a ladder down
from that room right up there.
Oh, well, that's strange.
Is that your room?
It might be.
But I certainly haven't seen
any men on ladders.
You just had sex with him.
- Oh, no, I didn't.
- You did.
- Did not.
- Then swear to God.
All right.
I swear to God.
You're a fucking liar!
I saw you dancing with that man.
That man you said you didn't know.
I'll pray for the safe return
of your birds.
Don't waste your breath.
Oh, God.
Ah!
Oh, shh, shh, shh...
I know. Okay.
Shh.
Hey, you hungry?
Hey!
Eat this, you idiot.
Here.
Come on.
_
You wanna know how I found you, Nora?
You want the truth?
When Matt told me you were gone,
I didn't believe him.
Or I couldn't.
I just-- I had this feeling
that you were still alive...
and that I would see you again.
And then-- then Matt died
and you weren't even at the funeral.
And that should've convinced me,
but I couldn't believe the last time
I saw you or talked to you
was in that fucking hotel room
that night I burned his fucking book.
I was so sure you were still alive,
even though everyone else in the world
said that you were fucking dead.
God, I...
I had to do something about it.
So I decided
that I was gonna look for you.
I was gonna start
right where I lost you.
Every year,
I have two weeks of vacation,
and every year,
I come to fucking Australia
and I show your picture
to everybody I meet.
"Do you know this woman?
Have you ever seen her before?"
And they all just look at me
and they shake their heads and they say,
"Oh, I'm sorry."
Everybody's so fucking sorry.
But I couldn't stop.
Every year, I would say to myself,
"I can't do this.
I'm not doing this.
Never again."
But every year, I would come back.
Because...
Because I couldn't stop.
And a couple days ago...
I showed your picture to that nun...
and I saw it in her eyes.
She recognized you.
She knew you.
And when I saw you...
I couldn't believe it.
There you were.
And I was so...
Oh, but I didn't know what to say...
...or where to start,
and so I just thought,
"Oh, fuck it. I'll erase it.
Just erase it all and maybe that
would give us another chance."
But you were right.
It's not true.
That's how I found you, Nora.
I...
I refused to believe you were gone.
You want some tea?
What?
I was gonna make a cup of tea.
You want some?
Okay.
You want one?
No. I quit.
Heart.
So, that part is true?
Mm-hmm.
That part is true.
What else is true?
Everything I said about Matt's funeral.
Everything I told you
about Jill and Tommy...
my father.
Did you move back to Mapleton?
No.
Still in Jarden.
In our house.
Anyone still call it Miracle?
Not so much.
How are the Murphys?
Uh, Michael's pretty much
running the church now.
I see Erika there
every once in a while.
She's great.
And John and Laurie
still live next door.
I talk to Laurie sometimes.
- What?
- Every once in a while.
Just when I need to.
- She knows you're here?
- Don't be mad at her.
She's my therapist.
She wasn't allowed to tell you.
Why didn't you tell me?
Because you were right, Kevin.
What you said in the hotel,
the last time we saw each other.
I needed to be with my kids.
Oh, no, I didn't mean that--
You meant it,
and you were right, Kevin.
There were always gonna be
bulletproof vests,
hugs from holy men...
tattoos to cover up.
But those were just ways
to deal with what I lost.
I needed a way to get them back.
I knew there was a chance
it would kill me,
but I made my peace with that.
And I said goodbye to my brother...
and I climbed right in.
And then you changed your mind.
No.
I didn't change my mind.
I went through.
I was in the parking lot,
naked...
curled up like a baby.
It was the same parking lot
I'd just been in,
except there were no trucks...
no people, no nothing.
It was cold, so I started to walk.
I walked by empty houses...
abandoned buildings.
And I found a store,
so I went in
and there were clothes there--
clothes hanging on racks--
so I got dressed
and I got back to walking.
I walked long enough
to convince myself
that I was the only thing
alive in that place.
And then night came,
and I saw lights, so I went to them.
It was a house,
and there was a man and a women there.
They were kind
and they told me...
the man told me
that seven years earlier,
he was in a supermarket
and every single person
disappeared except for him.
And the women told me
that she lost her husband,
her three daughters,
and all eight of her grandchildren.
And that's when I understood.
Over here, we lost some of them.
But over there, they lost all of us.
So, I went and did
what I came there to do.
I went to find my kids.
Planes don't really fly over there.
They have enough resources,
just not enough pilots.
So, I found a boat that would take me.
No boats go directly
from Australia to New York,
so it took me
a long time to get there.
A long time.
But I finally did.
And I walked through Mapleton.
I walked through
the town where I grew up...
where my parents died,
and Matt.
Where you and I met.
Most of the houses
were overgrown with weeds,
but the streetlights
still turned on at night,
and that made me feel less stupid
about expecting them
to still be there.
Still there in the very same house
where I lost them.
When I got there, I stood
behind a tree across the street
and I waited because I was too scared
to go up and knock.
And then, after a while,
the door opened.
At first, I didn't recognize them.
A tall teenage boy...
with curly hair...
and a girl,
maybe 11.
They were my children.
And then my husband came out,
and he was with a woman.
She was pretty.
She was pretty,
and they were all smiling.
They were...
happy.
And I understood
that here in this place,
they were the lucky ones.
In a world full of orphans,
they still had each other.
And I was a ghost.
I was a ghost who had no place there.
And that, Kevin,
is when I changed my mind.
The physicists who sent me through
told me the first person
to use the machine
was the guy who invented it.
His name was Dr. Van Eeghen.
I'm pretty sure
they were making fun of me,
but they said when I went over
that I should look him up, so I did.
That took a long time, too.
But I found him
and I asked him
to make another machine
because he already knew how.
And he asked me
if I had come all that way,
why in God's name did I wanna go back?
And I told him
it's because I didn't belong there.
So, he built it.
And I came back through.
I came back here.
Did I...
think about you?
Did I wanna call you?
Did I wanna be with you, Kevin?
Of course I did.
But so much time had passed.
It was too late.
And I knew that
if I told you what happened...
that you would never believe me.
I believe you.
You do?
Why wouldn't I believe you?
You're here.
I'm here.
www.addic7ed.com